NIRMAL SHAH Software Engineer

Somerville,MA| 781-475-3226 | <u>shahhr1cky@gmail.com</u> | <u>www.linkedin.com/in/nirmal-ricky-shah</u> | <u>www.nirmal-shah.com</u>

SUMMARY

I am a Full-stack developer who aims to create work that embodies uniqueness, creativity and clarity. I am a passionate human who works hard to offer creative solutions to help others in any way I can. My technical experience with Html, Css, Javascript, Node.js, React and PHP allow me to bring these creative solutions to life in digital spaces.

SKILLS & LANGUAGES

- HTML
- CSS
- SASS
- Javascript
- PHP
- Express.js

- Node.js
- Python
- Django
- React.js
- PostgreSql
- MySQL

- Bootstrap
- Bulma
- Git
- Github
- Wordpress
- AWS Cloud

PROJECTS

The Guitar World

Online website to purchase awesome guitars. Technology used Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Ejs.

Restaurants On The Go

An app to find top 10 restaurants from the cities around the world. Technology used React.js, Express.js. Health-Diary

App to track health related events. Technology used PostgreSql, React. is, PHP.

Song-Diary

Create a playlist of your favourite videos using embedded URI. Build using MERN stack.

Share-App

An app where you can share your blogs or thoughts. Build using PERN stack.

Pokemon-world

Pokemon app to find all the pokemons and their info. Build using HTML,CSS javascript and pokeapi.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Fellow, General Assembly

Aug 2020 - Nov 2020

- Developed competitive full stack web development skills with special emphasis on new technology and processes through a full-time immersive course.
- Worked independently and in small teams to deploy projects within strict deadlines.
- Converted mock-ups and designs into sleek responsive front end pages.
- Completed the cohort with 100% completeness of the home assignments

Guest service Aide + Front Desk Agent, Marriott Int

Apr 2019 - Mar 2020

- As a trainee, made keys for the guests using the Marriott PMS system.
- Helped the guests with the navigation around the hotel property and the city.
- Achieved nice comments from guests for being able to give them good services.

Cashier, Dunkin' Donut, Medford, MA

Jan 2019 - Dec 2019

- Handled a busy store with the orders, register and a very busy drive thru.
- Assisted manager with inventory and overall store operations.

Store Manager, Himalayan Brewery LTD, Lalitpur, Nepal

Feb 2014 - Nov 2018

- Prepared Monthly and yearly reports of the inventory for computation of balance sheet.
- Maintained records of incoming and outgoing inventories.

EDUCATION

- **General Assembly**, Software Engineering Certificate Remote
- United Academy, Faculty (Science) Nepal